Welcome! Today, we're going to master a phrase you probably use every single day – have
ようこそ！今日は皆さんが毎日使っているであろう「have to」というフレーズをマスターします。
to. What does it really mean and are you using it correctly? Well, let's find out.
その本当の意味を知っていますか？正しく使えていますか？一緒に見ていきましょう。
So, just think for a second. What's on your to-do list today? We all have one, right?
では少し考えてみてください。今日のあなたのToDoリストには何がありますか？誰にでもありますよね。
And that list is basically built around this idea of have to. It's the language we use
そのリストは、基本的にこの「have to」という考え方に基づいています。
for all our daily obligations.
日々の義務を表すときに使う言葉なんです。
Maybe it's a simple chore. When you say, I have to clean my room, you're not just
例えば簡単な雑用。「部屋を掃除しなきゃ」と言う時、それは単に
suggesting it's a good idea. No, you're saying it's a necessity. It's something
「やった方がいい」と提案しているわけではありません。そうではなく、それが「必要」なこと、
that just needs to get done.
つまり、やらなければならないことだと伝えているのです。
Or maybe it's some kind of external rule you've got to follow. Whether it's at
あるいは、従うべき外部のルールかもしれません。
school or at your job, these outside rules create a really clear obligation for us.
学校や職場などのルールは、私たちに明確な義務を生じさせます。
So here's the bottom line. Have to is all about things you're required to do, an obligation
要するに「have to」は、やらなければならないこと、つまり義務や必要性を表します。
or a necessity. It can come from an outside rule or just, you know, your own personal
それは外部のルールから来ることもあれば、単に自分自身の
plan. Think of it as a super close cousin to the word must.
計画から来ることもあります。「must」と、とてもよく似た言葉だと考えてください。
Now here's a quick pro tip for you. In a natural, flowing conversation, you'll almost
さて、ここでワンポイントアドバイスです。自然な会話では、
never hear a native speaker say, have to with a pause. Instead, it just kind of blends together
ネイティブが「have to」と区切って発音することは、ほとんどありません。代わりに音がつながって
into one sound, hafta. Go on, try saying it. I have to go. See? It just feels so much smoother,
「hafta」という一つの音のようになります。さあ、言ってみてください。「I hafta go」。ほら、
doesn't it?
その方がずっとスムーズでしょう？
Alright, let's dig into our first key rule. This one is all about who you're talking
では、最初の重要なルールを掘り下げてみましょう。これは、誰について話しているかに関わるルールです。
about. And honestly, it's the difference between sounding pretty good and sounding
これを理解すると、あなたの英語は「まあまあ」から
fantastic.
「素晴らしい」に変わりますよ。
The pattern here is actually really simple. For almost everybody, I, you, we, they, we
このパターンは実はとてもシンプルです。ほとんどの主語、「I, you, we, they」では
just use have to. But watch what happens when we're talking about just one other person
そのまま「have to」を使います。しかし、一人称・二人称以外の単数、
or thing, a he, she, or it. The verb changes and gets that S at the end, becoming has to.
つまり「he, she, it」について話すときは動詞が変わり、最後にSがついて「has to」になります。
And yep, you guessed it. The same thing happens with the sound here. In conversation, has
そして、ご想像の通り、発音も同じように変化します。会話では「has to」は
to becomes hasta. For example, he has to leave soon.
「hasta」となります。例えば、「He hasta leave soon.」のように。
Okay, time for a quick check to make sure you've got this down. Take a look at the
では、理解できたか簡単なチェックをしましょう。この主語を見てください。
subject. She. Which one do you think is correct here? Exactly! If you said has to, you nailed
「She」。どちらが正しいと思いますか？その通り！「has to」と答えたなら、大正解です。
it. Because she is a third-person singular subject, we need that S form, has to.
「She」は三人称単数なので、Sがつく形「has to」が必要になります。
Now let's see what happens to this rule when we start asking questions. Pay close
では、このルールが疑問文になるとどうなるか見てみましょう。
attention here, because this is where a really common mistake trips people up. But don't
ここは多くの人がつまずく、よくある間違いのポイントです。でも心配しないでください。
worry, we're going to make it crystal clear.
これから、はっきりと解説しますから。
So let's start with a simple positive statement. You have an obligation to study tonight. Easy
では、まず簡単な肯定文から。「You have to study tonight. (今夜、勉強しなければなりません)」。
enough.
簡単ですね。
Now to turn this into a question, we just pop the helping verb do right at the beginning.
これを疑問文にするには、文の最初に助動詞の「do」を置くだけです。
The rest of the sentence, you have to study, stays exactly the same. So far, so good, right?
文の残りの部分、「you have to study」は全く同じまま。ここまでは大丈夫ですね？
But what about this one? Here, our statement uses has to, because the subject is he. Now
では、こちらはどうでしょう？この文では、主語が「he」なので「has to」を使っています。
this, this is where the magic happens when we turn it into a question.
さて、これを疑問文に変えるときに、面白い変化が起こるんです。
So how do we ask this? A lot of people get this one wrong. So think carefully. What helping
では、どう質問すればいいでしょう？多くの人がこれを間違えます。よく考えてください。
verb do we need, and what happens to has to?
どの助動詞が必要で、「has to」はどうなるでしょうか？
And there it is. We use does because our subject is he. But look closely. Did you see it? The
答えはこうです。主語が「he」なので「does」を使います。でも、よく見てください。気づきましたか？
has to switched back to have to. So why does that happen?
「has to」が「have to」に戻っています。なぜこうなるのでしょうか？
Here's the key takeaway, and it's a big one. Think of it like this. The helping verb does
ここが非常に重要なポイントです。このように考えてください。助動詞の「does」が
is already doing all the heavy lifting. It has the S for the third person. And since
すでに三人称単数の「S」の役割を担っています。
you only need that S once in the sentence, has to can just relax and go back to its original
文中で「S」は一度だけでいいので、「has to」は元の形、
form, have to. So remember, in questions with do or does, it's always have to.
「have to」に戻るのです。ですから、「do」や「does」を使った疑問文では、必ず「have to」になります。
Okay, now we've reached what is probably the single most important distinction in this
さて、いよいよこのトピックで最も重要な違いにたどり着きました。
entire topic. The difference between these two negative forms is huge, and getting it
この2つの否定形の意味の違いは非常に大きく、これを正しく使い分けることが
right is absolutely key to clear communication.
明確なコミュニケーションの鍵となります。
First up, we've got don't have to. This one is simple and pretty friendly. It just removes
まず、「don't have to」です。これはシンプルで、優しい表現です。単に
the obligation. It means something isn't required. You can totally do it if you want,
義務がなくなることを意味します。つまり「～する必要はない」ということです。したければしてもいいですが、
but you don't have to. You've got a choice.
しなくてもいい。選択肢があるわけです。
And this is where the meaning becomes so critical. I mean, look at this. If someone says, you
そして、ここが意味の上で非常に重要な点です。これを見てください。誰かが
don't have to eat it, they're giving you a choice. Maybe you're full. No big deal. But
「You don't have to eat it (それを食べる必要はない)」と言ったら、選択肢を与えてくれています。大したことではありません。
if they say, you must not eat it, whoa, that is a strong prohibition. It's forbidden. Maybe
しかし、「You must not eat it (それを食べてはいけない)」と言われたら、それは強い禁止です。
it's dangerous. Maybe it's poison. As you can see, these two phrases are not interchangeable
危険なのかもしれないし、毒かもしれません。ご覧の通り、この2つのフレーズは
at all.
全く置き換えられません。
Okay, whew, that was a lot of ground to cover. So, let's bring it all together in one simple
さて、たくさんのことを学びましたね。では、すべてを一つの簡単な早見表にまとめて、
cheat sheet so you have everything you need in one place.
必要な情報がすべて一か所でわかるようにしましょう。
And here it is, your complete guide. You can see the whole system laid out right here.
これがあなたのための完全ガイドです。全体の仕組みがここに示されています。
The S-form, you know, has to and doesn't have to, that's only for he, she, and it. And notice
Sがつく形、つまり「has to」と「doesn't have to」は、「he, she, it」の時だけです。
how in any question, it always goes back to have to. But most importantly, you can see
そして、どんな疑問文でも必ず「have to」に戻ることに注目してください。しかし最も重要なのは、
that critical split in the negative forms, the one between giving a choice and stating
否定形での決定的な違い、つまり選択肢を与えることと、
a flat-out prohibition.
完全な禁止を述べることの違いです。
So let's end with this thought. This grammar stuff, it isn't just about passing a test,
では、この考えで締めくくりましょう。こうした文法は、単にテストのためだけのものではありません。
right? It's about understanding the difference between obligation and choice in your own
自分の人生における義務と選択の違いを理解するためのものなのです。
life. So, what's one thing you don't have to do, but you choose to do anyway?
さて、あなたが「する必要はない」けれど、それでもやると「選んでいる」ことは何ですか？
Thanks for joining me today.
本日はご視聴ありがとうございました。